Gustav Davidson Papers MS038
Digital Collections and Archives, Tufts University
Gustav Davidson Papers
1800 -- 1964
1613 -- 1986
Digital Collections and Archives, Tufts University
Davidson, Gustav
MS038
18.5 Linear Feet
Arrangement
This collection is arranged in two series: Personal Papers; Books and Ephemera.
Custodial History
Materials donated to DCA by Babette Bandler in 1999.
Scope and Contents
The majority of the collection consists of books from Davidson's personal collection; some correspondence, clippings, photographs and promotional brochures are interfiled with the books. Also included are photographs, clippings, diaries, correspondence, drawings, awards, poems, programs, bulletins, and publications. Much of the correspondence relates to Davidson's duties as Secretary of the Poetry Society of America, a position he held from 1949 to 1965.
Biographical / Historical
Gustav Davidson was born in Warsaw, Poland on December 25, 1895. His family moved to New York City in 1897. He received his bachelor's and master's degrees from Columbia University in 1919 and 1920 respectively. During the twenties and thirties, he wrote and published both dramatic works and poetry and founded and edited several literary magazines. In 1940 he founded Fine Editions Press. An integral part of the American poetry establishment through the 1960s, Davidson served as executive secretary of the Poetry Society of America from 1949 to 1965, after which time he was elected executive secretary emeritus. Also in 1965, he published his most well known book, A Dictionary of Angels, Including the Fallen Angels. Davidson married Mollie Strauss in 1942. He died February 6, 1971 in New York City.
Conditions Governing Access
This collection is open for research.
Davidson, Gustav; Poetry Society of America; Fine Editions Press; Arts
- Personal Papers, 1915 -- 1983; MS038.001; 2.9 Linear Feet
  Scope and Contents
  This series consists of photographs, clippings, correspondence, diaries, drawings, awards, poems, programs, bulletins, and publications.
  Much of this material relates to Davidson's work at the Poetry Society of America and to writers he knew. Also included is material related to his work with the Kennedy Foundation and the Steuben Glass "Exhibit in Crystal."
  Arrangement
  This series is arranged alphabetically by name or subject.
  Conditions Governing Access
  Open for research.
  - Ames, Beatrice: Photo album, loose photos of Marianne Moore and clipping, 1963 -- 1973; MS038.001.001.00001 (Box 1)
    Candid photographs of Gustav Davidson and Marianne Moore taken by Beatrice Ames
    Davidson, Gustav; Moore, Marianne
  - Bynner, Witter: Correspondence and photo, 1955 -- 1965; MS038.001.001.00002 (Box 1)
    Also includes copy of the "Santa Fe Scene" news journal from January 31, 1959
    Davidson, Gustav; Bynner, Witter
  - Berger, Oscar and Anne: Portraits, 1953; MS038.001.001.00003 (Box 1)
    Photos in cardstock frames with hand written notes by Anne Berger
    Berger, Oscar
  - Berger, Oscar: Correspondence and Clippings, 1957 -- 1973; MS038.001.001.00004 (Box 1)
    File includes envelope in which materials were housed when received by DCA
    Davidson, Gustav; Berger, Oscar
  - Berger, Oscar: Clipping, 1977; MS038.001.001.00005 (Box 1)
    Palm Beach Daily News, March 8, 1977 with Berger sketch of Amy Carter
  - Berger, Oscar: Drawings from Life Magazine and Photo, 1962; MS038.001.001.00006 (Box 1)
    Includes profile drawing of Robert Frost that appeared in Life Magazine
    Berger, Oscar; Davidson, Gustav; Frost, Robert; Poetry Society of America
  - Correspondence and "My Poetric Credo", 1954 -- 1968; MS038.001.001.00007 (Box 1)
    General correspondence and correspondence related to "My Poetic Credo" which was reprinted in _Poet Lore_ in Winter 1966
    Davidson, Gustav
  - Correspondence: General, 1934 -- 1953; MS038.001.001.00008 (Box 1)
    General correspondence is arranged in folders according to the groupings it was in when it was received by DCA
  - Correspondence: General, 1950 -- 1966; MS038.001.001.00009 (Box 1)
    Davidson, Gustav; Dorn, Alfred; Dunn, James Clement
  - Correspondence: General, 1955 -- 1970; MS038.001.001.00010 (Box 1)
    General correspondence is arranged in folders according to the groupings it was in when it was received by DCA; includes hand written poem by Edward J. Meyerson
  - Correspondence: General, 1958 -- 1970; MS038.001.001.00011 (Box 1)
  - Correspondence: General, 1965 -- 1967; MS038.001.001.00012 (Box 1)
    Davidson, Gustav; Marx, Anne; Ginsberg, Louis; Dorn, Alfred
  - Correspondence: General, 1967 -- 1970; MS038.001.001.00013 (Box 1)
    Davidson, Gustav; Angoff, Charles
  - Cummings and Anti-Semitism, 1951; MS038.001.001.00014 (Box 1)
    Response of New York B'nai Brith Anti-Defamation League to e.e. cummings' Seventy-one Poems"
    Davidson, Gustav; cummings, e.e.; Anti-Defamation League of B'nai B'rith
  - Davidson, Gustav: Address book, 1954 -- 1955; MS038.001.001.00015 (Box 1)
  - Davidson, Gustav: Award, 1951; MS038.001.001.00016 (Box 1)
    Poetry Society of America Alexander Droutzkoy Memorial Award, January 24, 1951
    Davidson, Gustav; Poetry Society of America
  - Davidson, Gustav: Awards, 1957 -- 1967; MS038.001.001.00017 (Box 1)
    Athens Committee of the Congress of European-American Associations and United Poets Laureate International
  - Davidson, Gustav: Biographical Information, 1967 -- 1971; MS038.001.001.00018 (Box 1)
    National Cyclopedia of American Biography
  - Davidson, Gustav: Poems, 1951 -- 1965; MS038.001.001.00019 (Box 1)
    Hand written and typescript poems by Davidson
  - Decker, Clarence: Correspondence, 1955 -- 1965; MS038.001.001.00020 (Box 1)
    Items originally housed together which is why they are separate from other Decker correspondence
    Decker, Clarence
  - Decker, Clarence: Correspondence, 1959; MS038.001.001.00021 (Box 1)
    Materials originally housed separately from other Decker correspondence
    Decker, Clarence; Davidson, Gustav
  - Ellis, Richard: Correspondence, 1938 -- 1964; MS038.001.001.00022 (Box 1)
    Ellis, Richard; Davidson, Gustav
  - Fay, Alice: Book Ephemera, 1915 -- 1936; MS038.001.001.00023 (Box 1)
    aka Countess di Castagnola
    Fay, Alice
  - Fay, Alice: Correspondence, Poems and Photos, 1929 -- 1959; MS038.001.001.00024 (Box 1)
    aka Countess di Castagnola; signed typescript poems
    Fay, Alice; Davidson, Gustav; Poetry Society of America
  - Fay, Alice: Poems, 1943 -- 1951; MS038.001.001.00025 (Box 1)
    AKA Countess di Castagnola; hand written and typescript poems
  - Fay, Alice: Will and Correspondence, 1952 -- 1953; MS038.001.001.00026 (Box 1)
    AKA Countess di Castagnola
  - Frost, Robert: Photographs, 1960; MS038.001.001.00027 (Box 1)
    Date is not confirmed
    Frost, Robert; Davidson, Gustav; Dorn, Alfred; Poetry Society of America
  - Ginsberg, Louis: Correspondence and Poems, 1967 -- 1968; MS038.001.001.00028 (Box 1)
    Ginsberg, Louis; Davidson, Gustav
  - Gogarty, Oliver St. John: Correspondence and Obituary, 1952 -- 1957; MS038.001.001.00029 (Box 1)
    Gogarty, Oliver St. John; Davidson, Gustav
  - Handley-Taylor, Geoffrey: Correspondence, 1959 -- 1968; MS038.001.001.00030 (Box 1)
    See Also: MS038/001-001#00040
    Handley-Taylor, Geoffrey
  - Hillyer, Robert: Correspondence, 1953; MS038.001.001.00031 (Box 1)
    Hillyer, Robert; Davidson, Gustav
  - Kaplan, Jeremiah: Correspondence and Gustav Davidson Poems, 1967 -- 1982; MS038.001.001.00032 (Box 1)
    Jeremiah Kaplan worked with the Macmillian Company during the publication of Davidson's _Dictionary of Angels_
  - Kennedy Center for the Performing Arts, 1961 -- 1965; MS038.001.001.00033 (Box 1)
    Event programs and publications
    Kennedy Center for the Performing Arts
  - Kennedy Family: Robert Sargent Shriver, Jr., 1963 -- 1964; MS038.001.001.00034 (Box 1)
    Signed correspondence and clipping
    Shriver, Robert Sargent, Jr.; Joseph P. Kennedy, Jr. Foundation
  - Kennedy Foundation, 1962 -- 1963; MS038.001.001.00035 (Box 1)
    Correspondence and event program regarding the Raphael Award. The award itself is made by Steuben Glass.
  - Kennedy Foundation, 1964; MS038.001.001.00036 (Box 1)
    Awards dinner guest list
    Joseph P. Kennedy, Jr. Foundation
  - Kennedy, Robert F.: Correspondence, 1964; MS038.001.001.00037 (Box 1)
    Signed letter thanking Davidson for his attendance at the groundbreaking for the JFK Center for the Performing Arts.
    Kennedy, Robert F.; Davidson, Gustav; Kennedy Center for the Performing Arts
  - Library of Congress: Correspondence, 1938 -- 1971; MS038.001.001.00038 (Box 1)
    Davidson, Gustav; Library of Congress
  - Lieberman, Elias: Correspondence and Book, 1958 -- 1976; MS038.001.001.00039 (Box 1)
    _Notation in Haste_
    Lieberman, Elias; Davidson, Gustav
  - Masefield, John: Photographs, 1960; MS038.001.001.00040 (Box 1)
    One contains no date; See Also: MS038/001-001#00030; Includes letter from Geoffrey Handley-Taylor dated 1960, and a photograph of John Masefield with T.S. Eliot examining the Caxton Chaucer, and a photo of John Masefield with H.M. Queen Mary which pre-date her death in 1953.
    Handley-Taylor, Geoffrey; Eliot, T. S.; Queen Mary
  - Masters Family, Correspondence and Book, 1970 -- 1971; MS038.001.001.00041 (Box 1)
    "Edgar Lee Masters: A Centenary Memoir-Anthology" by Hardin W. Masters
    Masters, Hardin W.; Masters, Edgar Lee; Masters, Marcia Lee
  - Masters, Marcia Lee: Correspondence, 1969; MS038.001.001.00042 (Box 1)
    Masters, Marcia Lee
  - Moore, Marianne: Photographs, 1967; MS038.001.002.00001 (Box 2)
    Moore, Marianne; Davidson, Gustav; Lowell, Robert; Poetry Society of America
  - Mullins, Helen: Reception, 1970; MS038.001.002.00002 (Box 2)
    Framed photo of John Hall Wheelock reading "The Mirrored Walls" by Helene Mullins
    Wheelock, John Hall; Davidson, Gustav; National Arts Club
  - Photographs: Labeled, 1953 -- 1970; MS038.001.002.00003 (Box 2)
    Dates are approximate; File also contains envelopes that originally housed photographs
    Sandburg, Carl; Doolittle, H.D. (Hilda); Buck, Pearl; Williams, Oscar; Marx, Anne; Decker, Clarence; Berger, Oscar; Graves, Robert; Solow, Herbert; Hughes, Langston; Davidson, Gustav; Poetry Society of America
  - Photographs: Portraits, 1931 -- 1960; MS038.001.002.00004 (Box 2)
    Dates are approximate, not all portraits are identified
  - Photographs: Unlabeled, MS038.001.002.00005 (Box 2)
    Four unidentified and undated photographs
  - Poet Lore and Poetry Society of America: Awards, 1959 -- 1967; MS038.001.002.00006 (Box 2)
    Poetry Society of America
  - Poetry Society of American: Bulletins, 1964 -- 1966; MS038.001.002.00007 (Box 2)
    February 1964 with drawing by Oscar Berger; November 1966 with picture of Robert Frost
    Berger, Oscar; Frost, Robert; Poetry Society of America
  - Poetry Society of America: Honorary Members, 1947; MS038.001.002.00008 (Box 2)
    List dated 2 December 1947 giving 12 Honorary Members of the Poetry Society of America
  - Poetry Society of America: Photograph, 1960; MS038.001.002.00009 (Box 2)
    Gustav Davidson with Clarence Decker and Richard C. Patterson participating in Proclamation of Poetry Week in New York City (April 11-18, 1960)
    Davidson, Gustav; Decker, Clarence; Poetry Society of America
  - Poetry Society of America: Photographs, Trip to Greece, 1957; MS038.001.002.00010 (Box 2)
    Parthenon; Ships; Poetry Society of America
  - Russell, Sidney King: Correspondence, MS038.001.002.00011 (Box 2)
    No date; Christmas card
  - Singer, Isaac B.: Correspondence, 1963 -- 1965; MS038.001.002.00012 (Box 2)
    Davidson, Gustav; Singer, Isaac B.
  - Solow, Herbert: Photographs and pamphlet, 1957 -- 1965; MS038.001.002.00013 (Box 2)
    Davidson, Gustav; Solow, Herbert
  - Speyer, Leonora: Correspondence, 1944 -- 1954; MS038.001.002.00014 (Box 2)
    Davidson, Gustav; Speyer, Leonora
  - Steuben Glass and the "Poetry in Crystal" Exhibit, 1962 -- 1963; MS038.001.002.00015 (Box 2)
    See also: Engraved Crystal by Steuben Glass and The Douce Apolypse by A.G. and W.O. Hassall in the second series. Davidson wrote a poem that accompanies on of the crystal scuptures produced by Steuben Glass.
    Davidson, Gustav; Steuben Glass
  - Steuben Glass: Photographs, 1963; MS038.001.002.00016 (Box 2)
    Davidson wrote a poem that accompanies on of the crystal scuptures produced by Steuben Glass.
  - Untemeyer, Louis: Correspondence, 1954 -- 1960; MS038.001.002.00017 (Box 2)
    Davidson, Gustav; Untemeyer, Louis
  - Williams, Oscar, 1957; MS038.001.002.00018 (Box 2)
    Williams, Oscar
  - Davidson, Gustav: Diary, 1928; MS038.001.003.00001 (Box 3)
  - Davidson, Gustav: Diary, 1935; MS038.001.003.00002 (Box 3)
  - Davidson, Gustav: Watercolored Poems, MS038.001.003.00003 (Box 3)
    No date; 3 copies of "Westbrook Marshes" (one with a dragonfly, one with flowers and one with a flowering branch)
  - Fay, Alice: Portraits, 1962; MS038.001.003.00004 (Box 3)
    Date based on telegram found with portraits; 6 sepia portraits
  - Life Magazine, November, 1983; MS038.001.003.00005 (Box 3)
    Featuring story on the Kennedy Assassination
  - The Saturday Evening Post, March, 1976; MS038.001.003.00006 (Box 3)
    Featuring an article "Presidents I Have Drawn" by Oscar Berger
  - Picture Frame, MS038.001.003.00007 (Box 3)
    No date; See MS038/002-007:00024 for photograph originally housed in frame; Photo dated 1931
- Books and Ephemera, 1613 -- 1986; MS038.002; 15.6 Linear Feet
  This series includes books and all related materials originally interfiled or located with these books. These materials include, but are not limited to, correspondence, clippings, photographs and promotional brochures. The majority of materials were removed from their corresponding books, rehoused in envelopes or folders, cataloged, and cross-referenced (book slips and finding aid). When interfiled material was not at risk of damaging a book, it was not removed. The description field contains a description of such items. Book cataloging includes: dedication/signature, publication information/first edition, condition and description, material/ephemera included, and what other material was stored in the same bag (most books had been stored in plastic shopping bags). Additional cataloging information is available in collection documentation folder.
  This series is arranged alphabetically by author's last name. Any related materials directly follow book listing.
  - Bag labels and miscellany, MS038.002.004.00001 (Box 4)
    No date; Many of the books were gathered together in plastic grocery bags, either by donor Babette Bandler or by the appraiser of the collection. The labels from these bags are collected in this folder. See individual book notes for indications of groupings.
  - Aldan, Daisy: Poems from India, 1969; MS038.002.004.00002 (Box 4)
    Dedication: For Gustav and Mollie -- Gratitude, Reverence and Love from Daisy Alden 1970; Thomas Y. Crowell Company Publisher; Good condition with only minor wear to dustjacket
    Poems
  - Alighieri, Danti and Lawrence Grant White, trans.: The Divine Comedy The Infreno, Purgatorio, and Paradiso, 1948; MS038.002.004.00003 (Box 4)
    Pantheon Publisher; Wear to edges of spine; Scraps of paper marking several illustrations; Illustrations by Gustave Dore and designed by Richard Ellis
    Dore, Gustave; Ellis, Richard; Alighieri, Dante
  - Ambers, Henry J.: The Unfinished Building, 1974; MS038.002.004.00004 (Box 4)
    Dedication: To Mollie with my warmest regards from Henry J. Amber; Edelweiss Press, Publisher; Slight discoloration of dustjacket
  - Analytical Psychology Club of New York: The Collective Unconscious in Literature, 1967; MS038.002.004.00005 (Box 4)
    Date is approximate; Dedication: To Gustav With affection Dorsha; Coated paper binding in good condition
  - Angoff, Charles: Memoranda for Tomorrow A Book of Poems, 1968; MS038.002.004.00006 (Box 4)
    Dedication: For Gustav and Mollie -- With gratitude for their friendship - and what they've done for the PSA -- and with the hope that we'll work together for many years to come -- Charlie January 30, 1969 Also signature of Gustav Davidson;T. Yoseloff, Publisher; Some wear to dustjacket
    Poems; Angoff, Charles
  - Angoff, Charles: The Bell of Time, 1966; MS038.002.004.00007 (Box 4)
    Dedication:For Gustav Davidson -- Major poet- Genuine friend - and all-embracing humanist -- Charlie Sept, 1967; Manyland Books Inc, Publisher;Breaking on edges of DJ, discoloration, clipping glued onto first flyleaf
  - Angoff, Charles: The Bitter Spring, 1961; MS038.002.004.00008 (Box 4)
    Dedication: For Gustav and Mollie -- With much affection and high regard -- Charlie August 18, 1963; Thomas Yoseloff, Publisher; DJ breaking on edges and spine;Article reprinted from The American Mercury entitled "Memorandum on Anti-Semitism" inside front cover; Author went to Harvard and was a newspaper man in Boston for a while; worked w/ H.L. Menckin; subject is Jewish family in Boston
    Angoff, Charles
  - Angoff, Charles: The Tone of the Twenties, and Other Essays, 1966; MS038.002.004.00009 (Box 4)
    Dedication: For Gustav -- From one fallen angel to another -- Charlie Oct 24, 1967; A.S. Barnes, Publisher; Wear to dustjacket
  - Artzibashev, Michaeland Percy Pinkerton, Trans.: Sanine, A Russian Love Novel, 1932; MS038.002.004.00010 (Box 4)
    Three Sirens Press, Publisher; Hinges are detaching, wear to corner covers
  - Ault, Norman: Elizabethan Lyrics from the Original Texts, 1925; MS038.002.004.00011 (Box 4)
    Dedication: To Walter with loads of love from Jo Sept. 20, 1928; Longmans, Green and Co., Publisher; Wear at bottom edge of spine; water spots of on top outer edge of textblock
  - Auslander, Joseph: Green World, a Book of Poems and No Traveller Returns, 1935; MS038.002.004.00012 (Box 4)
    Thin paper DJ completely torn and falling apart and in slipcase which is broken; originally in bag with The Winged Horse
    Poems; Auslander, Joseph
  - Auslander, Joseph: Letters to Women, 1929; MS038.002.004.00013 (Box 4)
    Signed by Harold Vinal; Published by Harper; Text block breaking, spine label cracked and faded; In bag with Sunrise Trumpets, Bittersweet poems, Marpessa and A Ballade Upon a Wedding; Bibliography card in textblock
  - Auslander, Joseph et. al.: The Winged Horse, 1930; MS038.002.004.00014 (Box 4)
    Dedication: 29th October 1937 For Gus, this copy of The Winged Horse whom none is worthier to ride: given with the admiration and affection of one of the stable grooms of Pegasus Jo; Doubleday Publisher; DJ in pieces and rehoused in envelope, rest of book is very good; Originally in bag with No Traveller Returns and Green World (in slipcase)
    Auslander, Joseph
  - Auslander, Joseph et. al.: The Winged Horse [Ephemera], 1930; MS038.002.004.00015 (Box 4)
    Dust jacket and clippings from The Winged Horse
  - Auslander, Joseph and Audrey Wurdemann: Sunrise Trumphets, 1924; MS038.002.004.00016 (Box 4)
    Publisher is Harper; Spine of dustjacket is completely detached; Originally in bag with Bitter-sweet Poems, Marpessa, A Ballade Upon a Wedding and Letters to Women
  - Auslander, Joseph and Audrey Wundemann, 1951; MS038.002.004.00017 (Box 4)
    Dedication: Inscribed for Gus and Mollie in the double bond of friendship and the fine fever of words with affection and admiration Joe Audrey July 11/51; Longmans, Green Publisher; DJ, pamplet, clipping and two letters rehoused; postcard and note left in place in text; 1st Edition
  - Auslander, Joseph and Audrey Wurdemann: The Islanders [Ephemera], 1951; MS038.002.004.00018 (Box 4)
    DJ, pamplet, clipping and two letters removed from The Islanders
  - Balzac, Honore de: The Comedy of Human Life, 1901; MS038.002.005.00001 (Box 5)
    3 volumes of a 36 volume set; From set 259 of 1,000 sets; Avil Publishers; Deckled edges and paper binding; Originally in bag labeled Comedy of Human Life de Balzac #259 3 vol; volumes 13, 18, and 19
    Balzac, Honore de
  - Bard, William B.: This Land This People, 1966; MS038.002.005.00002 (Box 5)
    Dedication: July 13, 1967 To Gustav Davidson - Upon reading "Aspects of Modern Poetry" and finding therein views so closely coinciding with mine, I was mended(?), I hope not too intrusivily, to present you with this volume Sincerely - W. E. Bard; Naylor Company Publisher; Very good condition; Bard was president of the Poetry Society of Texas
  - Barney, Danford: Selected Poems Old & New, 1942; MS038.002.005.00003 (Box 5)
    Fine Editions Press (Davidson's publishing house); Discoloration to dustjacket; Photograph was glued in but has detached and also order form in inside cover
    Poems; Fine Editions Press
  - Barr, Isabel: Jericho Road and Other One-Act Miracle Plays, 1949; MS038.002.005.00004 (Box 5)
    Dedication: To Gustav Davidson, with my best wishes, Cordially, Isabel Barr; Baker's Plays Publishing; Cover breaking at spine staple; Paperclip holding pages 7 through 18 removed
  - Baudelaire, Charles and Jacques le Clercq, Trans.: Flowers of Evil, 1958; MS038.002.005.00005 (Box 5)
    Dedication: For Gustav and Molly with the translator's liveliest affection and apologies Jacques October 1958; Peter Pauper Press; Good condition
  - Beaumont, Francis and John Fletcher: The Maides Tragedy, 1932; MS038.002.005.00006 (Box 5)
    Dedication: for my friend Gustav Davidson whose inspiring appreciation of my word has always been a source of great pride + stimulation. Richard W. Ellis Westport, CT at The Georgian Press; Cheshire House Publishing; Leather on spine deteriorating; paper is flaking; Number 86 of 1,200
    Poems; Ellis, Richard
  - Bennett, Richard, ed.: The Bedside Lilliput, 1950; MS038.002.005.00007 (Box 5)
    Dedication: Best wishes + love from Paul Xmas 1950; Hulton Press; Acid migration inside cover; inside of DJ is taped; Bibliographic card inside
  - Benton, Stuart: All Things Human, 1949; MS038.002.005.00008 (Box 5)
    See Also George Sylvester Viereck; Dedication: Courage! He who lost the day may have won the morrow! George Sylvester Viereck alias Stuart Benton; Price clipped, wear to DJ and bibliograpic card
  - Berger, Oscar: a la Carte, 1951; MS038.002.005.00009 (Box 5)
    Dedication: To Mollie with Best wishes for enjoyment of the culinary Oscar Berger New York April 1954; Hutchinson Press; DJ removed to envelope; water mark on front cover
  - Berger, Oscar: a la Carte [Dustjacket], 1951; MS038.002.005.00010 (Box 5)
    Dustjacket for book
  - Berger, Oscar: My Victims: The World-Famous Caricaturist Discusses his Art in a Gay and Instructive Book, 1952; MS038.002.005.00011 (Box 5)
    Dedication: To Gustav Davidson with my very best wishes for continued success with his wonderful poetry Oscar Berger New York September 1953; Harper Publishing; DJ is completely broken at spine; acid transfer from inserted correspondence (removed to envelope); Removed postcard and extra DJ and pencil drawing to envelope and folder
  - Berger, Oscar: My Victims: The World-Famous Caricaturist Discusses his Art in a Gay and Instructive Book [Ephemera], 1952; MS038.002.005.00012 (Box 5)
    Dustjacket, postcard and sketches
  - Berger, Oscar: The Presidents From George Washington to the Present, 1968; MS038.002.005.00013 (Box 5)
    Dedication: For Mollie & Gustav Davidson with warm greetings Oscar Berger New York October 1968; Crown Publishing, Very good condition
  - Bierstadt, Edward Hale:Dunsany the Dramatist, 1917; MS038.002.005.00014 (Box 5)